## RAYMOND MILLER

# PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Enthusiastic principal versed in preparing annual school budgets and implementing improvements to reduce costs. Ambitious with career success in building strong, effective teams of inspired educators and support staff. Over 18 years of experience in the academic landscape.

#### **WORK HISTORY**

#### PRINCIPAL 08/2012 to Current

Roosevelt Middle School, Watertown, SD

- Observe and evaluate teachers in classroom environment.
- Meet with parents to discuss students' academic performance and high school
- Establish after-school study program; provided on-campus supervision two days per week.

#### VICE PRINCIPAL 01/2008 to 08/2012 Lincoln High School, Watertown, SD

- Directed and organized weekly meetings with all faculty and staff.
- Provided chaperone supervision during dances, sporting events, etc.
- Collaborated with school counselors and district administrators to advise and support excessively truant or lower-performing students.

### HIGH SCHOOL BIOLOGY TEACHER 08/2004 to 12/2007 Great Plains Lutheran High School, Watertown, SD

- Taught AP Biology to three different groups.
- Tutored students for the SAT standardized test.
- Talked with students in need of extra attention and made plans to assist with concerns.

#### **EDUCATION**

**University Of South Dakota**, SD Master of Arts, Education Administration

Dakota State University, SD Bachelor of Arts, Education

## **SKILLS**

- School event coordination
- Microsoft Word and Excel
- Teacher and student development
- Curriculum development
- Safety and security procedures
- Group facilitation and presentations

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

South Dakota Teacher Certification (2004-current) South Dakota Principal Certification (2007-current)